Guide to the African American Jazz Preservation Society of Pittsburgh Oral History Project Records and Recordings, 1995-1999 AIS.1998.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Transcripts, 1995-1999; II.
  - Young, Curtis interviewed by Charles E. Austin, June 9, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    [T1S2] Other musicians; importance of identifying jazz performers; Union merger politics; value of historical documents; history of clubs and Local 471; present day politics; importance of jazz in black community; creation of bands.
  - Young, Curtis interviewed by Charles E. Austin, August 25, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Young, Curtis, (August 25, 1995), a drummer who performed in Pittsburgh discusses early history of Local 471.
    [T1S1] International drumming traditions; importance of reading music; opening Musicians' Club; WPA bands; Local 471 officer politics; historical information and documents.
    [T1S2] AAJPSP organizational matters.
  - Young, Curtis interviewed by Charles E. Austin, September 20, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Young, Curtis, (September 20, 1995), a drummer who performed in Pittsburgh discusses early history of Local 471.
    [T1S1] Discussion of early Local 471 members (alphabetical list); photographs of musicians.
    [T1S2] Other early musicians; Local 471 presidents; performing with bands; importance of early Local 471 history; practice bands; other musicians.
  - Young, Curtis interviewed by Charles E. Austin, Feburary 19, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Young, Curtis, (February 19, 1996), a drummer who performed in Pittsburgh discusses early history of Local 471.
    [T1S1] Map and location of Hill District clubs; musicians and Pittsburgh clubs. [T1S2] Other musicians; sports and performing; importance of accurate historical information; early Local 471 officers and politics; importance of primary source information.
  - Young, Curtis interviewed by Charles E. Austin, March 29, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Young, Curtis, (March 29, 1996), a drummer who performed in Pittsburgh discusses early history of Local 471.
    [T1S1] Map and location of Hill District clubs.
    [T1S2] Hill District clubs; discussion of research.
  - Young, Curtis interviewed by Charles E. Austin, June 17, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Young, Curtis (June 17, 1997), a drummer who performed in Pittsburgh discusses early history of Local 471.
    [T1S1] History of African American Musical Society; Elite Serenaders and other musicians from the 20s; Young family history; bee keeping and horticulture.
    [T1S2] discussion of group photograph and difficulties of oral history project.
  - Young, Curtis interviewed by Charles E. Austin, August 13, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Young, Curtis, (August 13, 1997), a drummer who performed in Pittsburgh discusses early history of Local 471.
    [T1S1] Discussion of early Local 471 members (alphabetical list); Local 471 officers; recent musician politics.
    [T1S2] Musicians Young performed with; opening Musicians' Club; Local 471 officers; musicians and bandleaders; beginnings of jazz; corruption in Union.
  - Young, Curtis interviewed by Charles E. Austin, November 28, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Young, Curtis (November 28, 1997), a drummer who performed in Pittsburgh discusses early history of Local 471.
    [T1S1] Pittsburgh bands and performers; oral histories project and archives; Pittsburgh performers; importance of preserving jazz history.
    [T1S2] Importance of correct information; process of preserving oral histories; Local 471 charter and Union cards; Pittsburgh clubs and organizations; jazz and Union politics.
- Project Working Files and Background Organizational Records, 1906-1999; III.
  - Correspondence Concerning AAJPSP OH Project (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - AAJPSP OH Project Proposed Partnership with University of Pittsburgh, December 3, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Database Report: Table of Interviewers/Interviewees (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - OH Project Policies and Procedures (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Release and Biographical Forms (A-L) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Release and Biographical Forms (M-Z) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Local 471 Members and Information Lists (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photocopies of Sample Membership Cards, Local 471 Musicians' Union (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Index to Local 471 Membership Cards (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Articles Submitted to The Pittsburgh Musician (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Discrimination Civil Action Suit (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Jazz Notes, Publication of AAJPSP (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Interview Between Curtis Young and Charles E. Austin, June 9, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Histories of Local 471 Musicians' Union by Bill Gambrell and Charles E. Austin (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript Draft:The Roots of the African American Musicians' Local 471 of the American Federation of Musicians in the City of Pittsburgh and Beyond by Shakura Ajsabur (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Program and Materials for the Back in the Day Celebration (Box 4, Folder 16)